MIGUEL CORREA

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

CONTACT

201-478-2295



miguelc1221@gmail.com



miguelcorrea.dev



mc1221 **in**



EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ART

Kean University 2008 - 2013

KFY SKILLS

HTML/CSS

JavaScript/Typescript

React

React-Native

Webpack

Cypress

Node.js/Express.js

Apollo/GraphQL

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Front-end developer with a passion for creating attractive user-friendly applications. A resourceful problem solver with a great deal of empathy for his users. Prefers working closely with designers in order to deliver the best user experience possible. Interested in code quality, design systems, migrations and building new features. Enjoys working with positive people and mentoring peers.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Ro, Remote | October 2021 - Present

Ro is a patient-driven Telehealth company that aims to be the patient's first call for all of their healthcare needs.

- Built checkout flow for a new product offering under the Roman brand.
- Migrated our marketing pages from Wordpress to Next.js.
- Contribute to discussions on aligning UI engineers and designers within Ro.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER III

Workday, Boulder, CO | January 2021 - October 2021

- Architected and built new features for the Workday People Experience platform.
- Worked with designers to quickly build features to A/B test.
- Contributed to Workday's design system component library.
- Helped other teams in the organization get up and running with React.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

Workday, Boulder, CO | June 2019 - September 2020

Workday is a cloud-based software vendor that specializes in human capital management, enterprise resource management, and financial management applications.

- Improved performance of our Enterprise Search application by
 - o Decreasing the JavaScript bundle by roughly 40%.
 - o Decreasing the time to first search result displayed by using server-sent events and the EventSource API to stream results to the client.
- Following a redesign, rebuilt our client-side application with React.
- Increased test coverage significantly in our client-side application.
- Worked closely with designers to improve UX and web accessibility.
- Assisted in maintaining our API written in Kotlin (Previously Node/GraphQL).

MIGUEL CORREA

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

INTERESTS

Traveling

Drawing

Sith Scale Figures Collection

Running

Hiking

Reading

RTS Games

EXPERIENCE - CONTINUED -

SENIOR FRONTEND ENGINEER

HelloFresh, New York, NY | October 2017 - June 2019

HelloFresh is a meal kit delivery subscription box service that delivers weekly boxes filled with pre-portioned ingredients.

- Assisted in the refactor of numerous internal applications which included migrating our last Angular application to React.
- As part of the USA retention team, I was able to quickly build and ship a feature that resulted in an increase of 15 million dollars in revenue.
- Paired program and mentored peers.
- Worked within an agile development environment while collaborating with designers, product managers and other engineers on a stealth startup within HelloFresh.

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Backbone Labs, Inc., San Mateo, CA | October 2016 - October 2017

Early stage Health tech startup aimed at reducing costs associated with back pain.

- Developed iOS and Android application using React Native.
- Bootstrapped our web application with React.
- Integrated Stripe in our web application.
- Maintained our Express.js node server.